Register of the Ray Lyman Wilbur papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- HERBERT HOOVER FILE, 1916-1964 (Boxes 19-21)
  - Correspondence
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1912-1948
      - 1912-1928 (Box-folder 21: 1)
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1927 April 11
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with typed Ls, 1 p., 4-to, Hopland, California, from George Hewlett to Herbert Hoover, 1927 November 30
        - 59 pieces of typed carbon correspondence from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, replies to letters, etc. (80 pieces, including correspondence with others, printed matter, etc.)
      - 1929 (Box-folder 21: 2)
        - Typed carbon L, 1 p., 4-to, N.P., from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, together with telegram from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur and typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 February 4, 9, 12
        - R. L. Wilbur miscellany, 9 pieces, including 2 typed Ls. 2 pp., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 April 26 and November 18
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 March 8
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with typed biographical memorandum, 1 p., 1929 March 11
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with typed carbon letter from H. Williams to George Akerson, 1929 March 12
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 March 14
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 March 25
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with a copy of a telegram, 2 pp., and newspaper clipping, 1929 March 23, 25
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with typed carbon memo, 2 pp., 8-vo, from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, 1929 March 23, 25
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Hoover to Wilbur, with typed copy of telegram, 2 pp., note from J. E. Hanway to Hoover, plus clipping, 1929 March 25
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Lawrence Rickey to R. L. Wilbur, with attached typed D, 3 pp., 1929 April 8
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 April 8
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, 1929 April 8
          Includes letter from Hoover to Wilbur, with carbon, 1 p., Wilbur to C. B. Ames, 1929 April 8.
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with a typed draft of a letter to governors of Wyoming, Colorado, and Utah, pencil manuscript corrections by Herbert Hoover, regarding oil conservation, 1929 April 10
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 April 10
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with two miscellaneous pieces of typed carbon correspondence, 1929 April 12
        - Two typed Ns, 2 pp., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur with manuscript notation on one, 1929 April 13
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 April 23
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 April 23
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 April 25
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 April 25
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 April 27
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with L, 1 p., from Harry Moore to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 April 29, May 1
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with newspaper clipping, 1929 May 1
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 May 6
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with legislative bill S4518, 1929 May 6
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with typed carbon reply, 2 pp., 1929 May 9
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 May 10
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Mrs. Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 May 17
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 May 17
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 May 22
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 May 24
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 May 31
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 October 4
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 October 4
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 October 16
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 October 27
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 November 11
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 November 12
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 November 16
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 November 23
        - Typed Ls, 1 p. (2 p.), 8-vo, Washington, from Mrs. Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 December 9
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 December 11
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 December 20
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, 1929 December 27
          First note signed by Herbert Hoover as President to R. L. Wilbur in the temporary office of the War and State Building following Christmas of 1929. With envelope.
        - Typed Ns, 1 p, 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with typed carbon N, 1 p., 8-vo, from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, 1929 December 31, 1930 January 3
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 December 31
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1929 December 31
        - Six miscellaneous typed and typed carbons of letters, etc., related to Herbert Hoover, together 6 pp
      - 1930-1932 (Box-folder 21: 3)
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1930 February 3
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1930 July 11
        - Typed report of governmental commission, 9 pp., 4-to, N.P., with two pencil notations on War Department stationery, 1930 December 23
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1931 January 8
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1931 January 15
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with letter from Strother to Wilbur and typed carbon letter, from R. L. Wilbur to Mr. Strother, 1931 February 18, 21
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur (R. E. Swain), 1931 March 14
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with typed carbon L, from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, 1931 March 16, 18
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1931 April 1
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1931 April 3
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1931 April 4
        - Typed Ls, 2 pp, 4-to, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1931 April 21
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1931 May 15
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1931 June 3
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with typed carbon letter, 1931 November 2, 3
        - 19 miscellaneous pieces (30 pieces), typed carbon L, correspondence, telegrams, etc.
          All related to Wilbur's position as Secretary of the Interior.
      - 1933-1936 (Box-folder 21: 4)
        - Typed carbon L, 1 p., 4-to, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to James Rand, 1933 February 25
        - ANs, 1 p., 4-to, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with ANs from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, copy of L from David Hinshaw to R. L. Wilbur, typed memo from E. Rickard to R. L. Wilbur, 2 pp., and typed copy of a letter from Mrs. W. B. Meloney to E. Rickard, 1933 March 23, 28
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1933 June 12
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L Wilbur, 1933 July 14
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L Wilbur, 1933 September 2
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1933 September 14
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1933 October 13
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1933 October 24
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1933 November 22
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1934 January 6
        - ANs, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1934 January 27
        - ANs, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, undated
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1934 February 6
        - ANs, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, undated
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L Wilbur, 1934 May 22
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with two typed carbons and typed Ns from T. F. Flaherty to Herbert Hoover, 1934 June 6, 8
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., From Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with typed carbon account of W. R. Hearst's interview with Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 1934 October 17
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P. from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1935 January 18
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P. from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1935 February 4
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P. from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with carbon reply from Herbert Hoover to Professor Haensel, with ALs from Haensel to Herbert Hoover, 2 pp., Los Angeles, 1935 February 3, 5
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1935 March 7
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1935 April 20
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1935 May 8
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1935 May 10
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, Stanford, from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover with manuscript pencil reply by Herbert Hoover at bottom of page, 1935 May 13
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 4-to, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with a typed carbon of a proposed speech of Herbert Hoover, "The Essentials of Social Growth in America," 15 pp., 4-to, N.P., and press release memo of speech, 11 pp., delivered at commencement exercises at Stanford University, 1935 June 9, 16
        - Two typed Ns, 2 pp., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1935 June 26 and 1936 February 20
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1935 September 11
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, Rochester, From Frank E. Gannett to R. L. Wilbur, with note from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, and Herbert Hoover's manuscript reply at top of letter, 1935 September 27
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 4-to, Boston, from Louis C. Cornish to R. L. Wilbur, together with typed carbon reply by R. L. Wilbur, 2 pp., 1934 November 16
          Herbert Hoover manuscript notation in upper left hand corner.
        - 20 miscellaneous pieces (32 pieces)
          Statements, notes, confidential memos, articles, reviews, letters about reviews relating to Herbert Hoover, with Herbert Hoover's penciled manuscript notations.
      - 1937-1941 (Box-folder 21: 5)
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1937 January 19
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1937 January 23
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 12-mo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1937 April 30
        - Telegram, 1 p., 4-to, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1937 September 18
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1937 September 19
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1937 October 6
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1937 October 18
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1937 November 6
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1937 December 23
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1938 January 14
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with a letter from Arthur White to R. L. Wilbur, San Francisco, 1938 January 21, 22
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1938 April 15
        - Hoover to Wilbur, 1 p., 1938 June 2
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1938 June 23
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1938 August 2
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1938 August 2
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1938 October 22
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1938 October 25
        - Miscellaneous correspondence, comprising typed carbon L from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, 3 pp., typed L from John S. Robinson to Herbert Hoover, 1 p. typed carbon reply from Herbert Hoover to Robinson, and covering memo, 1938 October 29
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1938 November 10
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1939 January 9
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1939 January 21
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1939 April 10
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with typed letter from V. E. Wilson to R. L. Wilbur and pamphlets, 1939 May 8
        - Typed carbon L, 2 pp., 4-to, N.P., from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, 1939 May 10
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with manuscript p.s. by Herbert Hoover, together with telegram from William Allen White, 1 p., 4-to, New York, and carbon telegraphic reply by R. L. Wilbur, 1939 October 2, 3, 5
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur. With manuscript notations by Herbert Hoover, 1939 October 13
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1939 November 2
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1939 November 6
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1939 November 19
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1939 December 12
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1940 January 9
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1940 January 22
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Stanford, from Lou Henry Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1940 January 31
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1940 February 14
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1940 March 27
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with letter from D. W. Lindsay, Arbuckle, California, and R. L. Wilbur typed carbon reply, 1940 May 28, 29, June 12
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1940 July 21
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1940 August 29
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with ALs from unrecognized correspondent to Herbert Hoover, 2 pp. (Guatemala Research, Washington, 1940 January 15), 1940 October 9
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1940 November 9
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1941 January 5
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with press release, 2 pp., letter from Hoover to Sol Bloom, 1941 January 15, 17
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1941 February 1
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1941 February 8
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with carbon reply by R. L. Wilbur, 1941 March 20, 29
        - Telegram, 1 p., oblong 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1941 April 3
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1941 May 10
        - Typed Ls, 2 pp., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1941 June 7
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to Dr. Leonard W. Ely, with typed carbon form letter, 1941 September 22, 25
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1941 October 9
        - ANs, 1 p., 4-to, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1941 October 21
        - Hoover to Wilbur, 1 p., 1941 October 31
        - AN, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, undated
      - 1942-1948 (Box-folder 21: 6)
        - 18 miscellaneous letters and carbon typed replies (21 pieces) by R. L. Wilbur re Herbert Hoover activities
        - Typed Ls, 2 pp., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1942 March 28
        - ANs 2 pp., 4-to, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1942 May 19
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur. With manuscript inscription, 1942 May 25
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1942 June 9
        - Typed carbon L, 1 p., 4-to, N.P., from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, 1942 August 3
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1942 October 3
        - ALs, 2 pp., 8-vo, San Francisco, from Mrs. E. Swift (to Hoover) with clippings, 1942 October 10
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1942 October 13
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1942 October 15
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with typed carbon manuscript, 1 p., 1942 October 19
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1942 December 13
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur. With typed memo, 2 pp., 1943 January 10
        - Telegram, 1 p., oblong 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1943 February 17
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1943 February 23
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1943 February 27
        - Six miscellaneous (3 only) typed carbon telegrams re Herbert Hoover (only 1 found), 1943 March 17-20
        - Typed carbon telegram, 1 p., 4-to, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1943 March 20
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1943 April 6
        - Typed Ls 2 pp., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur. With typed carbon reply, 1943 April 6
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, with long autograph post scriptum by Herbert Hoover, 1943 May 3
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with typed carbon attachment, 2 pp., 1943 May 14
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 4-to, New York, with typed carbon attachment to Herbert Hoover, 1943 May 31 and 1943 June 2
        - Typed carbon L, 1 p., 4-to, New York, from Bernard Baruch to Herbert Hoover, with typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1943 June 14, 18
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1943 June 21
        - ANs, 1 p., 8-vo, N.P., from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1943 July 24
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Stanford, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1943 August 14
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 4-to, Brattleboro, Vermont, from H. W. Mason (Republican National Committee) to Herbert Hoover; long manuscript note by Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur; typed carbon reply to Mason from R. L. Wilbur, 1944 April 25 and May 1
        - Three miscellaneous carbons of letters (5 carbons), 1944 May 1, 2, September 8, 23
        - Telegram, 1 p., oblong 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1944 September 26
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1944 October 1
        - ALs, 1 p., 4-to, N.P. (from Hoover to Wilbur) with two typed Ls, 4 pp. (plus clipping), from Arthur C. Clauser to R. L. Wilbur, 1944 October 22, 25, 30
        - Typed carbon L, 2 pp., 4-to, N.P., from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, 1945 February 2
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1945 February 14
        - Typed carbon L, 2 pp., 4-to, New York, from Herbert Hoover to A. Landon, 1945 February 18
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, curious letter about Japanese bacterial warfare, 1945 March 5
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, with typed carbon reply of a letter, 1 p., from Herbert Hoover to B. L. Werder, 1945 March 7
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1945 March 22
        - Telegram, 1 p., oblong 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1945 March 22
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1945 April 11
        - Typed carbon L, 1 p., 4-to, N.P., from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, with typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, a reply from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1945 May 14, 21
        - Typed carbon L, 1 p., 4-to, N.P., from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, with typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to W. Russell (plus Hoover to Wilbur, 1 p.), together with original letter of Russell to Herbert Hoover, 1 p., 4-to, New York, 1945 May 5, 6, 14
        - Typed carbon L, 1 p., 4-to, N.P., from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, with telegram, 1 p., oblong 8-vo, from The School of Liveable Christianity to Herbert Hoover with manuscript notations by Herbert Hoover, 1945 May 11, 15
        - Typed carbon of "Memo of Visit of Richard Bransten," 3 pp., 4-to, N.P., together with typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, New York, typed Ls, 1 p., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur; additional 5 miscellaneous typed pp. (plus Wilbur to Hoover, 1 p.), 1945 February 24, March 12, May 19, 22